<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data-lakehouse on anhcodes</title>
    <link>https://anhcodes.dev/categories/data-lakehouse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data-lakehouse on anhcodes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 22:13:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://anhcodes.dev/categories/data-lakehouse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Navigate Databricks FileSystem</title>
      <link>https://anhcodes.dev/blog/dbfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 22:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anhcodes.dev/blog/dbfs/</guid>
      <description> View Fullscreen View on Github </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The beauty of a data lakehouse</title>
      <link>https://anhcodes.dev/blog/data-lakehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 16:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anhcodes.dev/blog/data-lakehouse/</guid>
      <description>Choosing Enterprise Data Solution is a key challenge for modern businesses. With the explosion of data in recent years, organizations need to be able to store, manage, and analyze vast amounts of information to gain insights and make informed decisions. Data lakes, data warehouses, and data lakehouses are three popular solutions for managing data. However, Data Lakehouse has recently become a trend in distributed data management system
The battle: Data Warehouse vs Data Lake vs Data Lakehouse A data warehouse is a centralized repository that stores structured, processed data from a variety of sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Performance Tuning in Dedicated SQL Pool (Azure Synapse Analytics)</title>
      <link>https://anhcodes.dev/blog/query-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anhcodes.dev/blog/query-performance/</guid>
      <description>1. Best practices when Creating Tables 2. Identify slow-running QID and analyze compilation 3. Analyze the distributed query plan 4. Analyze a specific query plan 5. Analyze impacts of concurrent workload 1. Best practices when Creating Tables When creating table in Dedicated SQL Pool, choose the correct Distribution Column and Index for best query performance. Follow Best Practices in creating tables in Azure Synapse Analytics
Remember to create and Update Stats on your new tables Table statistics for dedicated SQL pool in Azure Synapse Analytics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices in creating tables in Azure Synapse Analytics</title>
      <link>https://anhcodes.dev/blog/create-table-azure-synapse-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 23:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anhcodes.dev/blog/create-table-azure-synapse-analytics/</guid>
      <description>As Dedicated SQL pool uses a scaled-out node based architecture, when creating tables in Dedicated SQL Pool, remember to specify the distribution (sharding strategy) and index for your tables.
Dedicated SQL Pool Architecture Choosing Distribution: The data is sharded into distributions to optimize the performance of the system. You can choose which sharding pattern to use to distribute the data when you define the table. These sharding patterns are supported:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Synapse Analytics - Data Lakehouse on Azure</title>
      <link>https://anhcodes.dev/blog/synapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anhcodes.dev/blog/synapse/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Table of Contents What is Azure Synapse Analytics? What is Dedicated SQL Pool? What is Serverless SQL Pool? Dedicated vs Serverless SQL Pool Comparison Azure Synapse Analytics, AWS Redshift, Google Big Query Comparison What is Azure Synapse Analytics? Azure Synapse Analytics is an integrated data platform that brings together SQL technologies used in enterprise data warehousing such as Dedicated SQL Pool and Serverless SQL Pool, Synapse Spark Pool used for big data, Data Explorer for log and time series analytics, Synapse Pipelines for data integration and ETL/ELT, and deep integration with other Azure services such as Power BI, CosmosDB, and AzureML.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
